Now, there's a couple other tasks that are really helpful.
现在，还有一些其它有用的 task
You'll see before I went ahead and just deleted artifacts and deleted the cache manually.
你应该还记得我之前是用手动方法删除的 "artifacts" 和缓存
Well, to do that yourself, you can also just run yarn Hardhead, clean.
你自己做的时候也可以运行这个 "yarn hardhat clean"
And that'll delete the artifacts folder and clear out your cache.
这样做就会删除 "artifacts" 文件夹并清除你的缓存
We already know what compiled does.
我们已经知道 "compile" 是在干什么了
But one of the biggest things that Hardhead is fantastic for especially is running tests.
但 hardhat 最大的优点之一其实是非常适合运行测试
Now we haven't run tests yet so far.
目前为止我们还没有运行任何测试
However, running tests is absolutely critical to your smart contract development journey.
但是，测试环节对于你的智能合约开发之旅绝对至关重要
And we're going to spend a lot of time in the future writing really good tests.
未来我们将会花费大量时间来编写良好的测试
The reason that writing tests are so important
之所以编写测试如此的重要
is because we want to make sure our code does exactly what we want it to do,
是因为我们希望确保我们的代码确实能够实现我们想要的功能
especially in the defy, and the decentralized, smart contract world,
在 DeFi 以及去中心化智能合约的世界中尤其如此
all of our code is going to be open source for anybody to interact with, and potentially exploit.
我们所有的代码都将对所有人开源以供其交互，并有可能被利用
There's sites like req dot news,
有一些网站比如说 "rekt.news"
which go through a ton of previous hacks and how they actually got hacked
它们会介绍大量之前的黑客攻击事件还有他们是如何被攻击的
and what happened in the smart contract to enable these hacks to occur.
以及智能合约中到底发生了什么才导致了这些攻击的发生
So testing, so writing really strong tests is always going to be our first line of defense.
所以说编写一个强大的测试永远是我们的第一道防线
And we have this sample test.js,
我们这里有一个 "sample-test.js"
that comes default with the basic package of hardhat.
它是 Hardhat 默认自带的一个基础包
But as you probably already know,
但你可能已经猜到了
we're going to rename this and change it.
我们将把它重命名并进行修改
So we're going to rename this to test deploy dot j s.
我们将把它重命名为 "test-deploy.js"
And we're going to delete everything in here and start from scratch.
并删除其中的所有内容从头开始
We want to be able to test all of our solidity code locally,
我们希望能够在本地测试所有的 Solidity 代码
so that we know exactly what it's doing.
以便我们知道它正在做什么
And we can have a programmatic way to make sure that our code does what we want it to do.
我们可以通过编程的方式来确保我们的代码会按照我们期望的方式运行
So let's write a basic test for our simple storage contract.
所以让我们为我们的 "SimpleStorage" 合约写一个基本的测试
So that we can be sure that it's doing exactly what we want it to be doing.
这样我们就可以确认它是否在执行我们想要的操作
Hard Hat testing works with the Mocha framework,
Hardhat 测试使用的是 Mocha 框架
which is a JavaScript based framework for running our tests,
它是一个基于 JavaScript 的框架用于运行我们的测试
you actually can write tests directly in solidity, if you'd like to,
你甚至可以直接用 Solidity 来编写测试，如果你想的话
there's a bit of back and forth on whether testing with pure solidity is better or testing with a modern programming language.
关于使用纯 Solidity 进行测试更好还是使用现代编程语言进行测试更好存在一些争议
The argument goes that testing with a modern programming language,
支持现代编程语言进行测试的论点是
you have more flexibility to do more stuff to interact and test your smart contracts.
你会拥有更大的灵活性来对你的智能合约进行更多的交互和测试
But the argument for testing with us with solidity is that
但支持使用 Solidity 进行测试的论点认为
we want to be as close to the code as possible.
我们希望尽可能接近这个代码(即测试用的代码和编写智能合约用的代码相同)
At the time of recording,
在录制的这个时间点
most projects do the vast majority of their testing in a modern programming language like JavaScript.
大多数项目都在使用现代编程语言进行测试例如 JavaScript
So that's what we're going to be using here.
所以我们这里就用这个
So to get started with our mocha tests,
要想开始我们的 Mocha 测试
we do, we're going to write a describe function.
我们要写一个 "describe" 函数
Describe is a keyword that hardheaded mocha will recognize,
"describe" 是一个关键字，Hardhat 的 Mocha 将会识别它
and it takes two parameters, it takes a string,
并且它有两个参数，第一个接收的是一个字符串
which we're going to just write simple storage for now.
我们要写进去的就是 "SimpleStorage"
And then also takes a function,
第二个接收的是一个函数
we could make function, test func and then write some stuff in here,
我们可以创建一个函数，名为 "testFunct"，并在这里编写一些内容
and then pass it to our describe here.
然后把它传递到 "describe" 这里
But the common convention is going to be to do is to make it as an anonymous function,
但通用的约定是让它成为一个匿名函数
which we can create by typing function, putting an empty parameter here,
我们可以输入 "function"，放置一个空参数
and then some brackets like that.
然后加上花括号来创建它
So our describe function takes a name, a string, and a function.
所以我们的 "describe" 接收一个名称字符串和一个函数
Another way that you'll often see functions in describe is using that anonymous function syntax.
你经常可以在 "describe" 中见到另一种匿名函数的使用方式
So you might see just these parentheses, an arrow, and then some brackets,
你可能会看到一组括号，一个箭头，然后是一些花括号
the two of these are going to be basically the same,
这两种方式基本上是等价的
there are some differences. And this second one is actually best practice,
区别就是，第二个在实际使用中是最好用的
but just know that you might see this arrow syntax in other tests as well.
但你也要知道你可能会在其它测试中见到这种箭头语法
We have described a sample storage and then our function here,
这里我们已经拥有了 "describe"，一个 "SimpleStorage" 和一个函数
which is going to have all of our tests in it.
这就是我们的测试所需要包含的全部内容了
Inside each one of our describe blocks.
在每一个 "describe" 的代码块内
We're gonna have something called a before each, and a bunch of It's
我们都会有一个 "beforeEach" 和很多 "it"
Our before each function is going to tell us what to do before each of our hits.
"beforeEach" 函数会告诉我们在我们的每一个 "it" 之前要做什么
So we're going to have a ton of it and then we're going to have a before each.
所以我们会有很多 "it" 而只有一个 "beforeEach"
All of our IDs are going to be where we actually write the code for running our tests.
所有的 "it" 就是我们实际编写运行测试代码的地方
And before each is going to be some code that tells us what to do before each one of these hits,
而 "beforeEach" 则会告诉我们每个 "it" 之前需要做些什么
we can also actually have describes,
我们实际上还可以这么做 "describe"
inside of describes, which again have more before each and more before it's
在这个 "describe" 内，又可以有更多的 "beforeEach" 和 "it"
having these nested describes can be really helpful for separating and modularizing our tests.
这些嵌套的 "describe" 能很好的帮助我们分离和模块化我们的测试
But for this one, we're just going to have a setup that looks like this.
但对本次测试，我们将只需要一个这样的配置
And for this demo, we're only going to have one it.
并且在这个 demo 中我们也只有一个 "it"
So in order to test our smart contracts,
为了测试我们的智能合约
before we actually run our tests, we're probably going to need to deploy the smart contracts first.
在实际运行测试之前，我们可能需要先部署智能合约
So inside of our before each,
因此在我们的 "beforeEach" 中
we're going to pass the our before each a function,
我们将传递一个函数给我们的 "beforeEach"
that's going to tell our testing framework what to do before each test.
它会告诉我们的测试框架每个测试前都要做些什么
So we're going to pass it an async function like this.
所以我们要传入一个 "async function"，就像这样
And in here, we want to deploy our simple storage contract.
然后在这里，我们要部署我们的 "SimpleStorage" 合约
So to do that, we're going to need to get the ethers framework
为了做到这一点，我们需要获取 ethers 框架
and do exactly what we did in our deploy script.
并执行我们在 "deploy" 脚本中所做的完全相同的事情
So in here, we're at the top we're gonna say const.
所以这里，我们要在顶部执行 "const"
Ethers, equals require art have
" = require("hardhat")"
an import ethers from hard hat.
并把 ethers 从 Hardhat 中导入进来
Then in our before each function,
接着在我们的 "beforeEach" 函数中
we'll say await ethers dot get contract factory of simple storage.
我们将执行 "await ethers.getContractFactory("SimpleStorage")"
And we'll assign this to a const. Simple Storage factory.
并将其赋给一个 "const" 变量 "simpleStorageFactory"
And then we'll run away, simple storage factory dot deploy.
然后我们要运行 "await simpleStorageFactory.deploy"
Cool.
OK，酷~
And let's also assign this to a variable cost simple.
让我们把它也赋给一个变量 "const simpleStorage"
Now, since right now, our simple storage and simple storage factory are scoped just to inside the before each,
现在，由于我们的 "simpleStorage" 和 "simpleStorageFactory" 只在 "beforeEach" 内部可见
we actually need to stick these variables outside of the before each,
我们需要把这些变量从 "beforeEach" 中移出来
so all of our events can interact with them.
这样所有事件都可以与它们进行交互
So instead of having simple storage, factory, and simple storage, be constant variables,
所以我们不再将 "simpleStorageFactory" 和 "simpleStorage" 定义为常量变量
we're going to define them outside of them for each with the let keyword.
而是使用 "let" 关键字将它们定义在 "beforeEach" 之外
And we're gonna say let simple storage factory
我们要做的就是 "let simpleStorageFactory"
and we're going to initialize it to nothing.
并将其初始化为空
And then we'll say led simple storage.
接着是 "let simpleStorage"
Now, if you have a whole bunch of let's just initializing
现在，如果你有很多 "let" 要初始化的话
another way, you can write them in JavaScript,
那么你可以用 JavaScript 的另一种方式来编写它们
just let simple storage factory comma, simple storage.
只要写成 "let simpleStorageFactory, simpleStorage"
And that works exactly the same.
这样做的效果是完全一样的
And then we can get rid of this const keyword.
然后我们就可以把 "const" 关键字去掉了
Because it's not a constant since we are assigning it.
因为它不再是一个常量了，我们给它赋了值
And now we have simple storage, factory and simple storage
现在我们有了 "simpleStorageFactory" 和 "simpleStorage"
that we can use inside of our init function.
就可以把它们用在我们的 "it" 函数中了
Now we have a before each section.
现在我们有一个 "beforeEach" 部分
So before each one of our tests, we're going to deploy our simple storage contract.
因此在我们的每个测试之前，我们都会部署一次 "SimpleStorage" 合约
So we have a brand new contract to interact with for each one of our tests.
这样我们每次测试都有一个全新的合约可供交互
Now, inside of the ID, this is where we're going to say what we want this specific test to do,
现在在 "it" 内部，我们要说出想做的测试具体要做什么
and then describe the code that's going to actually do that.
然后描述出实际执行此操作的代码
So we're going to say it
所以我们要输入 "it()"
should start with a favorite number of zero.
"should start with a favorite number of 0"
So this is saying what this test should do.
所以这里就是在说这个测试该做什么
And then we're going to add our async function to actually do that.
然后我们要添加一个异步函数来实际执行这个操作
So we'll say async function.
所以我们输入 "async function"
And in here, this is where we'll actually write the code to make sure that our contract does exactly this.
接着在这里，我们将编写代码来确保我们的合约会按照我们所期望的方式运行
We're say const. Current Value, equals await, simple storage.re retrieve.
我们要写 "const currentValue = await simpleStorage.retrieve"
And now in this test, we want to say okay,
现在在这个测试里，我们想要做的就是
now check to see that this current value is indeed zero. So how do we do that?
检查 "currentValue" 是否确实为 0，该怎么做呢？
Well, we can say const, expected value is going to equal zero.
可以这么做 "const expectedValue = "0""
And what we can do is we can do either we can use either the assert keyword, or the expect keyword,
我们可以使用的是 "assert" 或者 "expect" 关键字
which we're going to import both of these from a package called Chai.
它们都可以从一个名为 "chai" 的包中导入进来
We actually installed Chai automatically
我们其实已经自动安装了 "chai" 包
when we downloaded the basic parameters when we downloaded the basic packages for hardhats.
就是在我们下载 Hardhat 等基础包的时候
So at the top, we're gonna say const. Expect and assert equals require Chai,
所以在顶部，我们要输入 "const  = require("chai")"
I'm a big fan of using assert as much as possible,
我非常喜欢尽可能多地使用 "assert"
because I think the syntax makes a little bit more sense.
因为我认为它的语法更加合理
But there will be scenarios where we need to use expect instead.
但某些情况下我们也需要使用 "expect"
Now, assert has a ton of functions that are built in
"assert" 内置了很多函数
that help us make sure this is what we expect it to be.
它们可以帮助我们确保一切如我们所期望的那样运行
So I can do assert dot equal current value.to string,
所以我们可以执行 "assert.equal(currentValue.toString())"
because remember, this is actually going to be a big number,
因为要记得，这里实际上是一个大数
comma, expected value.
", expectedValue"
So I'm saying I'm asserting this retrieve to return zero,
所以我在断言("asserting")这个 "retrieve" 的返回值是 0
which is going to be our expected value.
也就是我们的 "expectedValue"
Now to actually run this,
现在要实际运行这个测试
we're going to run yarn, art hat test.
我们需要执行 "yarn hardhat test"
And we see we get an output that looks like this
我们可以看到输出的结果如下
should start with favorite number of zero, and it's indeed passing.
"favorite number" 应从 0 开始（即刚才在 it() 中输入的那句话），并且它通过了测试
You'll notice that if I were to change this to one,
你会发现，如果我把这里改成 "1"
and this wasn't correct, it would break
它是不正确的，会报错
and it would say art Pass or not passing
并且它会显示我们的测试没有通过
assertion error expected zero to equal one.
断言错误：预期 0 等于 1("AssertionError：expected '0' to equal '1'")
It expected zero to equal one, which is not what we want.
它期望 0 等于 1，这不是我们想要的
We want zero to equal zero. So let's run this again.
我们想要的是 0 等于 0，让我们再运行一次
Tada should start with favorite number zero, and it's passing.
看吧，"favorite number" 应从 0 开始，并且已经通过了
Alright, fantastic. So that's how we wrote one of our tests,
非常好，这就是我们要编写的测试之一
let's write one more test just to make sure that things are good.
让我们再写一个测试以确保一切安好
So let's say it should update when we call store,
这次我们说 "Should update when we call store"
because when we call the store function, we want our favorite number to update.
因为当我们调用 "store" 函数时，我们希望 "favorite number" 会更新
And we'll make this an async function as well. And let's add our stuff in here.
让我们把这个函数也设置为异步函数，并在这里添加我们的代码
So we'll say const. Expected Value equals seven,
现在我们可以说 "const expectedValue = "7""
we're expecting that when we call store it updates to seven.
我们期望在调用 "store" 函数时它会更新为 7
Now we can say const. Transaction response equals await simple storage dot store.
现在我们输入 "const transactionResponse = await simpleStorage.store"
And we can even just pass it the expected value here.
我们甚至可以直接把 "expectedValue" 传给这里
And then we'll do a weight transaction response that weight one.
然后我们执行 "await transactionResponse.wait(1)"
Now let's get the current value.
现在让我们获取当前值
So we'll say const. Current Value equals weight, simple storage, retrieve.
"const currentValue = await simpleStorage.retrieve"
And now we're going to assert dot equal current value.to string, comma expected value.
现在我们执行 "assert.equal(currentValue.toString, expectedValue)"
And now we can run all these tests by running yarn Hardhead test.
现在我们可以通过运行 "yarn hardhat test" 来运行所有这些测试
And you'll see we ran both of these tests.
你会看到我们运行了这两个测试
And now if I have 10,000 tests, and I'm only finagling with one test,
现在如果我有 10000 个测试，但我只想运行其中的一个
I can actually just run one test by running yarn, art app, test, dash dash grep.
我可以这样做 "yarn hardhat test --grep"
And I can search for any keywords in any of the text here.
我可以搜索这里的任何文本中的任何关键词
So I'm going to grep for the store function.
我将在这里搜索 "store" 函数
Because the store keyword isn't in this tax for this, it, it's only in the text for this it.
因为 "store" 关键词不在这个文本里出现，它只在这个文本里出现
So if I do grep store, it should only run our second test,
因此如果我运行 "grep store"，它应该只会运行我们的第二个测试
which does indeed,
它确实做到了
one other way we can run only specific tests is with the only keyword.
另一种只运行特定测试的方法是使用 "only" 关键字
So we can type it dot only like that. And then we can run yarn, art hat test.
我们可以输入 "it.only" 就像这样，然后运行 "yarn hardhat test"
And it should only run, this should update when we call store.
它应该只会运行这个 "Should update when we call store"
And it does indeed,
确实如此
then we'll go ahead and delete this save, run again, and it should run all too. Fantastic.
我们删除这个，保存，再次运行，它应该会再次运行所有测试，太棒了
Now the other way you'll see these tests written is with instead of assert, it'll use the expect keyword.
你可能会见到另一种编写测试的方式，使用的不是 "assert" 而是 "expect" 关键字
So you'll see something like expect current value.to string.to dot equal expected value,
你会见到这样的语句 "expect(currentValue.toString()).to.equal(expectedValue)"
the two of these lines do exactly the same thing.
这两行代码做的是完全相同的事情
And it's sort of up to you on which one you want to use.
你可以根据自己的偏好来选择使用哪一种
And that's all we're going to do for our testing. Now.
这就是我们现在所要做的所有测试了
This is fantastic, great job.
太棒了，干得不错